

EDUCATION

2020 - 2023

- Front-end for Designers
- UI Design

CareerFoundry

2009 - 2010 M.Phil Film Theory & History

Trinity College Dublin

2003 - 2007 B.A (Hons) Fine Art IADT Dún Laoghaire

UX / UI SKILLS

Prototyping
Agile
Wireframing
High Fidelity Mockups
Design Systems
Branding
User Personas
UX Research
User Flows
UX Research
A/B Testing
Competitor Analysis
Visal Design

SOFTWARE

Sketch
Figma
InVision
Usability Hub
Framer
Miro
Notion
Airtable
GitHub
Jira

LANGUAGES

English (native) German (B 2.1) Spanish (B 1.2)

Tess Motherway

www.tessmotherway.com

0176 2547 7564 tmotherway@gmail.com 10245 BLN

PROFILE

UI Designer with a background in Film & TV production, Arts & Culture and Creative Education with a focus on UX, research, front-end development and accessibility - skilled at designing for education, data privacy, healthcare & scientific publishing. Highly inventive & curious individual with excellent visual storytelling & creative problem solving expertise. Realises & guides creative projects from conception to final delivery through strong analytic & lateral thinking skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI Designer

SpringerNature Digital

NOV 2021 - PRESENT

- Shaped design approaches to magazine paywall strategy & access routes to content.
- Paired with front-end developers, designed rapid concepts for new interaction, helped plan UX work & align design patterns across different brands.
- Designed improvements for content aggregation pages that drive usage & help researchers understand new topics.
- Collaborated with other UI Designers to help develop brand styleguides for growing design system and coordinate with journal platform teams.
- Spearheaded visual design work that led to improved experiences for users on nature.com
 & SpringerLink as migration to newer technology.

Lead UX/UI Designer: Education

OpenMined

FEB 2021 - NOV 2021

- Redesign of web interface for online data privacy courses 'The Private AI Series' with stakeholders Facebook AI, Oxford University & the United Nations to improve project submission flow & course completion rates using Human Centred Design approaches.
- Conducted Existing Product, Competitor & SWOT analysis and analysed site statistics & key metrics to determine key areas of opportunity against benchmark of established user profiles, define project impact statement & drive design decisions.
- Formulation of user, preference & A/B testing to gain user insights around project submission flows & identify key areas of frustration to improve student engagement & assignment completion rates.
- Conducted user interviews, polls & surveys to gather insights into user behaviours, pain-points & desirable functions.
- Synched workflows with Education team & Developers through inter-departmental workshops, design sprints & iterative design processes.

UX/UI Designer

Squirrel News

OCT 2020 - NOV 2021

- UX research & workshop facilitation designed & facilitated 'Impact statement' & 'Define audience' workshops to align team on product goals & user groups.
- Conducted Existing Product, Competitor & SWOT Analysis.
- Strategised & designed new website CTA's for newsletter sign-ups & donations using improved visual hierarchies resulting in a spike in both since implementation.
- Founded first branding & style guide & introduced a design system for enhanced workflow & collaboration.

Tess Motherway

www.tessmotherway.com

tmotherway@gmail.com 10245 BLN

0176 2547 7564

Customer Service Specialist

N26

FEB 2020 - MAY 2020

- Main information point of contact. Provided excellent customer support via live chat & email.
- Upheld secure verification processes, kept abreast of all company policies & app updates.
- Informed copywriting & development team of any inaccuracies & technical errors in Confluence database.

Main Film Viewer

Interfilm Short Film Festival

FEB 2020 - AUG 2020

• Viewed, rated & categorised over 400 short film submissions for inclusion in festival programme 2020 according to excellence in visual storytelling, production, acting, camera, sound & rhythm.

Event Manager

Macromedia University

JUN 2019 - NOV 2019

- Development, co-ordination & management of all campus, academic & sales events including Open days, biannual Graduation & Fashion Shows.
- Formulated new concepts with Marketing & Admissions team to visually promote Macromedia at events including;
 event invitations, branding and prospectus materials.
- Established first student events team (100+ students) creating work experience opportunities while simultaneously supporting Marketing team with staffing, location preparation & testimonials.

Lecturer

SEPT 2018 - NOV 2019

- Design, concept & delivery of Scriptwriting & Dramaturgy lecture series to BA (Hons) Design students.
- Guided class exercises & discussions, peer critiquing, individual tutorials & pitching sessions.
- Oversaw successful delivery & grading of all final short film scripts.
- Curated programme of short films, visiting lecturers & festival outing to Interfilm Short Film Festival.

Admissions Assistant

BIMM Berlin & Hamburg

FEB 2017 - MAY 2019

- Assistant to Head of Admissions BIMM Berlin & Hamburg Modern Music Institutes.
- Processed & assisted 300+ students from point of application through to successfull enrollment.
- Represented BIMM at fairs & open days working closely with Events & Recruitment team to devise new ways to promote BIMM through visual merchandise, promotional materials & visual presentations.
- Strategised with international marketing team on website UX, communication streams, applicant user flow, branding & outreach campaigns.
- Created first Admissions Assistant document archiving all details of the role for training & circulation.

